[Music]
hi Tik Tok it's been a minute since I've
posted anything and I just wanted to
give you an update um this video was
shot exactly 3 months after Hurricane
Helen hit Asheville and it looks so
similar that sometimes it's
discouraging um this is builtmore Avenue
on December
27th that's the McDonald's they are
going to remodel it right down here in
builtmore Village um
I'm just going to take you on on a
little spin a little loop around
builtmore Village the most affected
areas still look pretty bad um you can
see the linemen are still here they are
still working on power in some areas um
none of the stores or restaurants in
this area are open buil more estate is
open but as you can see none of these
stores have been able to resume
operation
this road is now open to through traffic
they've cleared the debris out enough
that you can take a spin through here
but um none of the the retail spaces are
open there's Kataba Brewings uh one of
Kataba Brewings locations there on the
right and if we turn here and we head up
the hill we will go right past um French
Broad River Brewing and then also um on
the right you can see in this little
area right here as we head up toward
District departments you can see erine
Distillery and they are working on
getting both of those cleaned up and
resuming
operations um somewhat normally now if
we go and cut through the district
Department uh parking lot we come down
here past where there was a coffee shop
and and a little Bike Shop um we are
going to intersect right here with
Thompson Road and I'm going to go ahead
and take a right on Thompson Road and
take you down toward um Brother Wolf and
Asheville te and all of that Thompson
Road there's the dog park that was right
across from uh rivermill Lofts
Apartments uh it's just it's just gone
it's still gone
um again we're we're 91 days in this is
exactly 3 months and the devastation was
so much this is swanana NOA river right
here and the river banks on swanana NOA
were green and Lush lots of trees lots
of growth you couldn't see across the
way barely the cars they're still here
they're marked the X means that it was
checked for bodies and because there's
no further mark Kings um they did not
find anyone deceased in that vehicle and
Thompson Road or Thompson Street excuse
me runs parallel to swanana NOA River
Road which is the road that we're
looking at across swano River here and
and again it just is still devastated
and this is for all intents and purposes
downtown Asheville it's part of
builtmore village and I'm just going to
go ahead and pull into this parking lot
here because they've actually closed
Thompson Street again so we were able to
go through um I'm going to go ahead and
get out and walk and I'll take you on a
little itty bitty walking tour here you
can see there's the
barricade um apparently there's been
more damage to the road and as it rains
and as the weather comes and goes the
roads continue to to crumble in certain
places because all of the earth
underneath it is moving and has shifted
and they're saying this is the second
worst geological event in US history
that there were over 2,000 landslides
and you know that in addition to the
flooding um it was a geological event so
you can still see that the cars are
stuck in Swan River the shipping
containers I know it doesn't look like a
very big river but when you see a
shipping container in there you have a
better idea and I'm going to go ahead
and get back in the car and I'm going to
drive down Thompson Street back toward
builtmore Avenue because lots of people
have asked me about the old Tobacco Barn
and there's um River Mill Lofts
Apartments huge apartment complex it was
condemned because the entire first floor
and the parking garage was just washed
out if you look um over this way you'll
see the old Tobacco Barn or where it
used to be wnc tile was washed away and
there has been massive debris cleanup
but it still looks terrible I heard that
the amount of debris that needs to be
cleaned up and moved um and the amount
that has been cleaned up and moved is
about 4% of what needs to be done so
just a tiny fraction even though they're
taking out literal tons of debris um but
as promised the old Tobacco Barn is up
here it's going to be on the right
across the river because it sat on Swan
NOA River Road and if you're not
familiar with the old Tobacco Barn it
was a
77,000 square foot
warehouse and um people you can see the
debris being removed there
and people sort of
consigned vintage and antique items
there and lots and lots of people loved
to shop and to come to Asheville to
visit the Tobacco Barn you can see the
shell of it up here on the right it's
the black um building once we get past
this little Bluff here you'll be able to
see it a little bit better but it was
completely washed out and if you can
imagine
77,000 Square ft of retail space
and all of the inventory because it was
packed to the gills lots of vendors had
little booths there and had space there
and would resell vintage and antique
items but everything is gone from that
space over here that's where Asheville
Mortuary was located and that building
was completely washed away the mustard
colored building there that's the paper
company and we are continuing on down to
um built more Avenue
again there's the old Tobacco Barn or
the shell of the old Tobacco Barn there
and you can see the river and you can
see how much debris is still left and
how much Greenery is gone you you
couldn't see a cross here barely because
there was so much kudu and Shrubbery and
trees but now it's just a
wasteland and they are not allowing
people to drive down swanana NOA River
Road over there unless they're in there
working so you will see a car or two but
for the most part um that road remains
completely closed so when we come up
here we've done a loop and we will come
back to the intersection of Thompson
Street and builtmore Avenue and you can
see this area was underwater if you've
seen any of the Drone footage it was
underwater
up to the restaurant signs the rooftops
were covered and all of this and you can
see the debris and the trees and get an
idea of just how high the swan NOA River
as it was meeting the French Broad River
how high the flood waters were that
right there is is Moe's Burrito Barn
it's completely hollowed out they've
been removing debris but it's completely
decimated and then you can see the
Japanese restaurant
and you couldn't barely see the Long
John Silver sign from the Drone footage
because the flood waters were so high
they were above this gas station here
and so you can imagine the chemicals and
the waste in the water it's been
terrible but yeah 91 days later that's
what builtmore village still looks like